9 Mallard Lane, Long Valley NJ, 07853

C: (908)894-4056 carolynrosecuesta@gmail.com

Summary

Creative and enthusiastic teacher of music with a wide range of experiences. Organized and highly driven, with an ability to differentiate lessons and reach all students. Motivated to enhance all students' musical experience through varied methods of teaching.

Education

Moravian College, Bethlehem, Pennsylvania

Bachelor of Music in Music Education (K-12)

3.53 GPA

Graduating on May 13th, 2017

Named to the Dean's Honor List in Fall 2016, Spring 2015, and Fall 2014.

Teaching Experience

Student Teacher

Zephyr Elementary School – Whitehall-Coplay, Pennsylvania

January, 2017- March, 2017

Instrumental Music, Grades 4-6

- Conducted group lessons on wind band instruments in grades 4 and 5.
- Developed lesson plans for wind band instrument groups.
- Rehearsed a selection for the annual "Bands in the Round" concert during biweekly band practices.
- Developed rehearsal plans for biweekly band rehearsals.
- Conducted two selections during the annual "Bands in the Round" concert.

Pre- Student Teacher

Orefield Middle School - Parkland, Pennsylvania

September, 2016 - December 2016

Instrumental Music, Grades 6-8

- Developed rehearsal plans for daily band rehearsal
- Taught individual lessons to beginning players during larger band rehearsals.
- Served as a guest conductor during the winter concert.

Farmersville Elementary/ Freemansburg Elementary -Bethlehem, Pennsylvania

February, 2016- May 2016

General Music, Grades K-4

- Planned and taught lessons involving the use of Orff instruments, movement, and singing
- Instructed and created lessons including cross curricular subjects
- Planned lessons using universal design to benefit students of all backgrounds

Relevant and Leadership Experience

Moravian College Academic Support Center- Bethlehem, Pennsylvania

September 2014- Current

Tutor

- Communicated between students and professors to determine most effective means of tutoring students.
- Met with students weekly for one-on-one tutoring sessions in Music and beginning level Spanish classes
- Organized and held drop in tutoring hours for all Music students

Orchestrated group review sessions for exams

Moravian College Community Choir- Bethlehem, Pennsylvania

August 2016- Current

Secretary

- Organized communication between director and ensemble members
- Kept record of ensemble members' attendance
- Responsible for communicating information about rehearsals and performances to ensemble members

Gamma Sigma Sigma, Epsilon Xi - Bethlehem, Pennsylvania

January 2016- January 2017

Executive Board Member, Secretary

- National community service sorority member, fulfilling a minimum of 20 hours of community service per semester
- Attended general and executive board meetings
- Organized all communication between chapter and philanthropic partners and district supervisor
- Organized communication between executive board and general members

Moravian College Wind Ensemble- Bethlehem, Pennsylvania

January 2016- May 2016

Assistant Section Leader/Librarian

- Organized, distributed, and collected music from entire ensemble
- Facilitated sectional rehearsals with the flute section of the ensemble.
- Communicated between ensemble members and director in matters regarding the ensemble

Episcopal Church of the Mediator- Allentown, Pennsylvania

August 2014- December 2014

Choral Section Leader, Alto

- Helped to teach music to alto section of choir
- Facilitated choral rehearsals and performances during church services

Performance Experience

Vocalist, Alto, Moravian College Community Choir (Fall 2014- Present), Moravian College Women's Choir (Spring 2015- Fall 2015), Vocalis (Select A Cappella Ensemble) (Fall 2014-Spring 2016), Moravian College, Bethlehem, Pennsylvania

Flautist, Moravian College Orchestra (Fall 2015- Spring 2016), Moravian College Wind Ensemble (Springs 2015 and 2016), Flute Ensemble (Spring 2016- Fall 2016) Moravian College Marching Band (Falls 2013-2014) Moravian College, Bethlehem, Pennsylvania

Performed in multiple concerts throughout the year, including student composition concerts and recitals.

Percussionist, Moravian College Marching Band (Falls 2015-2016), Moravian College Community Orchestra (Fall 2013- Spring 2015)

Marching bass drum and auxiliary percussion

Work History

Sales Associate, Village Super Market, Chester, New Jersey (Summer 2016)

- Controlled cash drawer of more than \$2,000
- Provided excellent customer service and worked with a diverse team of staff members
- Assisted with the training of new employees

Sales Associate, Donaldson Farms, Hackettstown, New Jersey (Seasonally, 2014-2015)

- Controlled cash drawer
- Provided distinguished customer service and information
- Worked with a diverse team of employees
- Assisted with training new employees in cash register operation
- Evaluated stock and quality of merchandise